Guide to the Bostlemann Family Papers, 1848-1938
Department of Special Collections
Bostlemann Family Papers,
1848-1938
Special Collections M0075
.5 linear ft.
Stanford University. Libraries. Dept. of Special Collections and University Archives.
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
None.
Provenance
Gift of Hayward State College, 1963.
Biography
Bostelmann, Karl Louis Georg, painter, born: January 22, 1825 in Hannover. Copied from 1840 at the Gallery of Dresden. In 1843, he went to Venice, Florence, and Rome, where he stayed from 1844 to 1846. From 1847 to 1866, he was in the employment of the Court of Hannover as a miniature portrait painter. He painted numerous miniature portraits of the royal family and the family of the Crownprince of Oldenburg. He also painted large oil portraits. After 1866, he was working in and about Hamburg, then again in Hanover. Since 1858 he owned a mansion in Wachholz bei Beverstedt, where he later retired as a private citizen.
Scope and Content
Letters of Karl Bostlemann (b. 1825), German miniature portrait painter, his wife, children, daughter-in-law, and grandchildren written from Germany and the U.S., mostly in German. Includes a history of the King's German Legion by N. Ludlow Beamish printed in 1832. The book has hand executed illustrations and mentions Bostlemann's father. Also includes manuscript notes in English by Carl, Jr., written in 1935.
Access terms
Beamish, North Ludlow, 1797-1872; Bostlemann, Karl Louis Georg, 1825; Bostlemann, Carl; Bostlemann family; King's German Legion; Germany--Emigration and immigration; United States--Emigration and immigration
Container List
- Groups of the Bostelmann Correspondence
  - To Carl Bostelmann by different people in Beverstedt -Wachholz, 1848 - 1900
  - To Carl Bostelmann in Hannover by his wife, Johanna from Beremrhaven, 1854
  - To August Bostelmann in Hoboken, N.J. from family in Wachholz, 1868 - 1875
  - To Carl Bostelmann (Jr.) in Hoboken, N.J. from family in Wachholz, 1875
  - To Carl and August in Hoboken, N.J. from family in Wachholz, 1875
  - Carl from Newark, N.J. to August in Hoboken, N.J., 1874
  - To parents in Wachholz from Carl and August in Hoboken, N.J., 1875
  - Johanna Bostelmann's bound letters, reminiscences, miscellaneous writings, 1881
  - Carls's letters from Chicago and Lenison, Iowa to family in Wachholz, 1878, 1881
  - August's and family's letters from Lutherville to parents, 1888
  - Mathilda (Mrs. Carl) Bostlemann to her mother, 1889, 1890
  - Carl the elder to Carl Jr. to Ponca, Nebraska, 1906, 1908
  - Amelie and Carla Bostelmann to grandparents in Wachholz, 1901
  - To Amelie in Ponca, Nebraska from Breverstedt, 1907
  - To Carla in Ponca, Nebraska, 1909
  - To Carl in Ponca, Nebraska from brother Ernst in Holt, N.Y. and from Los Angeles, 1909
  - To Carl in Ponca, Nebraska from brother Ernst in Los Angeles, 1909
  - To Carl at 1255 West 88th Street, Los Angeles, 1918
  - To Carl at 1558 So. Arlington, Los Angeles, 1923
  - To Carl at 11216 or 18 Burbank, North Hollywood, 1928, 1931
  - Mathilda's letter from Hollywood to daughter Amelie (Mrs. Lightner) in San Francisco, 1938